# DAKOTA HOLIMAN

# Human Focused UX Designer

- Lehi, Utah
- **4** (435) 233-8529
- 👆 dakotaholiman.com
- □ dakota.holiman@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/dakota-holiman

#### **SUMMARY**

With extensive training for this position from its previous occupant, I am well prepared and confident I will excel in this role. In fact, since the previous UX Design Manager left the company, I've assumed his responsibilities and continued his ongoing projects. While the department is now understaffed for the workload, I have navigated the complex business and time limitations to provide high-fidelity, thoroughly tested user experience solutions.

#### **HARD SKILLS**

Adobe XD, Applied branding, Color theory, CSS & HTML Development, Design systems, Figma, HCl design, High-fidelity mockups, Illustrator, Information hierarchy, Lightroom, Photography, Print design, Prototyping, UI/UX design, User testing, Visual hierarchy, Wireframing

### **SOFT SKILLS**

Active listening, Adaptability,
Attention to detail, Collaboration,
Communication, Creativity, Critical
thinking, Curiosity, Empathy,
Evaluation, Organization,
Open-mindedness, Problem-solving,
Project management, Reliability,
Time management

## REFERENCES

**Andy Untch**: (330) 904-0763 **Dave Wade**: (801) 326-0582 **Victor Hubbard**: (801) 326-0582

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **UX/UI Design Manager II**, Young Living Essential Oils

June 2021 - PRESENT

- Lead projects, designing solutions, and overseeing handoff to development
- Ensure adherence to brand and UX systems for consistent user experience
- Incorporate user research and usability tests into design decisions
- · Estimate project effort and plan accordingly
- · Collaborate with stakeholders, developers, and content managers
- Support complex Agile and Waterfall delivery systems

## Senior UX & Graphic Designer, Performance Driven Marketing

May 2019 - June 2021

- Created visual branding and digital design systems for custom websites
- Collaborated with developers to create custom Wordpress themes that allowed complex features while maintaining operating efficiency
- Managed visual design projects including print, layout, and branding

# Visual Designer, Freelance

January 2017 - PRESENT

 Provide design services for various clients, including product design, ux systems, web design and basic front-end web development, logo and brand ecosystems, layout and print materials.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Fine Arts, Graphic Design**

Southern Utah University, College of Performing and Visual Arts

2016 - 2018

- GPA 3.78
- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- · Dean's list every semester
- · Founder's Scholarship

## **Associate of Science, General Studies**

Southern Utah University, College of Science and Engineering

2012 - 2014

- GPA 3.84
- President's Award for Outstanding Academic Excellence
- National Society of Collegiate Scholars
- · Dean's list three of four semesters